# **JOHN GREEN**

0418120955 | jgreen@ionus.com.au | Malvern East, VICTORIA 3145

https://linkedin.com/in/john-francis-green | https://ionus.com.au

#### **PROFILE**

I am a motivated and analytical Software Developer of 30 plus years' experience. I am proud of my solid track record of delivering projects including real-time and embedded, many of which were considered difficult. My skills include analysis, design, coding and documenting working software. Interests are in programming languages and computer graphics. I also enjoy doing embedded software and dabbling in Assembly. Available for immediate start and for remote or local employment.

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

Masters Preliminary - University of Western Australia

Bachelor of Applied Science (Computer Science) - RMIT University

#### **SKILLS**

- C & C++
- Assembly & embedded
- Shell Scripting, Python, Perl
- Java & Java VM

- FORTRAN & PASCAL
- JavaScript, HTML & CSS
- Icon, Swift & Kotlin
- Realtime & multitasking
- QNX & QNX Windows
- X Windows & Qt
- Linux, Unix & OS-9
- MS Windows & DOS

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## DIRECTOR/OWNER - IONUS PTY LTD (1993 - Present)

 Ionus Pty Ltd was started in 1993 with the objective to produce bespoke software mostly in the technical, engineering & manufacturing sectors

- Experienced Managing Director with a demonstrated history of working in the computer software industry
- Skilled in C, Python, Linux, QNX & Embedded systems

# LINUX NETWORK DEVELOPER - HAMMOND STREET DEVELOPMENTS (2018 – 2018)

Written tests for testing performance of various applications

- Analysis & study of performance critical code
- Wrote Bash scripts to run tests

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - QUINTESSENCELABS (2012 – 2018)

- Developed C KMIP client API product for VMWare's products. Included a language to describe Key Management functions
- Developed APIs for PKCS#11

- Wrote a simple CI for configuring the QuintessenceLabs
  Key Manager product
- Preliminary worked on a Java, Python & C# interface to the KMIP client API
- Tested the Key manager Web UI with Selenium

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BUREAU OF METEOROLOGY (2012 – 2012)

- Ported C Programs from HP-UX to Linux
- Utilised C & Git
- Programs accessed the Bureau's databases

 Added a textual interface in addition to the current binary interface

#### FIRMWARE CONSULTANT - AXXIN (2012 – 2012)

- Consultant on firmware matters
- Wrote firmware using eclipse & Mercurial
- Extensive testing of algorithm & parameters
  - · Recording of the results

# SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - FREESTYLE ENERGY (2007 - 2011)

- Designed, wrote & supplied software consisting of updates & improvements to the C compiler, assembler & linker
- Wrote the Librarian to take advantage of the improved linker
- Designed & wrote ports of the Freestyle Virtual Machine

- Co-designed & wrote Freestyle RTOS
- Ported the Freestyle VM to uC/OS Operating System including file system
- Ported VM & Freestyle RTOS to PIC24 processor
- Ported the VM to Linux
- Developed handlers for various communication platforms such as Zigbee & Coronis

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - SYMSTREAM LTD (2006 – 2007)

Developed & wrote the subsystem for the Symstream gateways

Using C & UDP for the subsystem, utilising Python

#### SYSTEM SUPPORT/SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - ACTTAB (2005 – 2006)

- Supported the ACTTAB wagering system day-to-day operations
- Liaised with operations staff

- Wrote FORTRAN code for maintaining the ACTTAB wagering system
- Wrote software that interfaced ACTTAB to TABCORP for the ACTTAB wagering system in FORTRAN

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - IONUS PTY LTD (2004 – 2005)

- Wrote software in PERL to extract data from mini discs
- Web site set up & development
- Written PHP & Java accessing MySQL on Linux
- Simple web development on Linux & Apache using HTMI
- Helped colleagues with HTML, Java & JavaScript

## SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - OMEGA INDUSTRIES PTY LTD. (2001 – 2004)

- Supplied software to Omega Industries Pty Ltd.
  Software consisting of:
- C compiler for a VM & VM assembler

- VM, Operating System and Flash file system on a PIC micro processor
- Algorithm & support software application running on the VM

#### C/C++ PROGRAMMER - ERICSSON AUSTRALIA (2000 – 2001)

- Fixed problems made enhancements to proprietary software
- Improved performance considerably where previously it failed to meet requirements
- Consulted with team members to help improve another problem to an acceptable level

#### SATELLITE PHONE PRODUCT DEVELOPER - NEC AUSTRALIA (2000 – 2000)

- Developed improvements to the S2 satellite phone production test
- Developed code on QNX tester to manage & perform satellite phone calls
- Designed & implemented a protocol & MIB for the S2 phone
- Implemented the S2 protocol & MIN on the S2 using OS9

## PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE ENGINEER - IONUS PTY LTD (1999 – 2000)

- Supplied software to the Department of Defence with NEC Australia
- Produced a version of the DEFAUSSAT software previously supplied for doing local monitoring
- Tested software for Y2K compliance

- Provided many copies & delivered them to site with testing
- Provided training courses on site for all recipients of the software

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER - NEC AUSTRALIA (1999 - 2000)

- ICONet Project
- Verification & Validation of the Terrestrial Network Manager (TNM) software with ICONet
- Developed interface to communicate with & configure the new RPN (Solaris based VME system) for ICONet
- Wrote simulations of loads & performance of the TNM in Visual Basic
- Assisted with the design of the MMI for the TNM for ICONet
- Specification of the MMI screens
- Assisted in the development of the portable load generator & the implementation of the SS7 messaging
- Coded up the messaging for simulation for MT & MO calls based on GSM with ICO's specific additions for the portable load generator (call simulator)

#### RADIO DESIGN & DEVELOPER - NEC AUSTRALIA (1997 – 1999)

- Updated legacy software for the production testing of satellite phones
- Designed & implemented a MIB in the S2 satellite phone. The S2 uses OS-9
- Designed & implemented a language to describe the MIB & a compiler to compile the MIB
- Designed a transmission protocol & messaging similar to SNMP based on OSI Managed Objects

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - CONVERGENT SYSTEMS (1996 - 1996)

- Worked on a custom GIS for Bell South with Convergent systems in C++
- Was consulted on ideas for a radical way of improving the system
- Wrote C++ code to make the GIS comply with Bell South requirements

#### PRINCIPAL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - IONUS PTY LTD (1994 - 1995)

- Supplied software to the Department of Defence with NEC
- Designed, programmed, implemented & delivered a new implementation of the Defence Australia Satellite (DEFAUSAT) Earth station
- Developed to monitor software running on QNX & QNX windows in C

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BHP PETROLEUM (1993 – 1994)

- Contracted to port graphics plotting program written in FORTRAN from DEC VMS to HPUX
- Developed graphics using GTK

- Produced some other support programs as required
- Documented the porting effort

#### TEST COORDINATOR - TELECOM AUSTRALIA (1993 – 1994)

- Test coordinator for Telecom's TESAMS system
- Coordinated the test engineer team, consisting of 30+ staff from all over Australia over a 6-month period
- Designed & wrote many of the test cases
- Recorded & tracked the testing progress

#### SENIOR ANALYST/PROGRAMMER - TUSC COMPUTER SYSTEMS (1987 – 1993)

- Wrote extensive software in FORTRAN, C & PASCAL on HP1000 RTE-A, HP-UX & DOS
- Developed software on DOS using PASCAL

- Developed ME for Telecom Australia for the TESAMS project. First ME in Australia, using ASN.1 to C
- Developed Relational database interfaces & innovative solutions to real-time problems

## SYSTEMS ENGINEER - HEWLETT-PACKARD (1984 – 1987)

- Delivered courses in FORTRAN to customers
- Supported HP Technical User Group & held customer accounts
- Wrote FORTRAN code inhouse to correct problems
- Provided phone in support for HP1000 RTE-A systems for southern Australia

## SYSTEMS PROGRAMMER - DEPARTMENT OF LANDS AND SURVEYS (1980 – 1984)

- Wrote relational database system in FORTRAN, Landsat image processing software in FORTRAN, other applications in FORTRAN
- Considerable FORTRAN code & assembler on PDP-11 RSX-11M & some UNIVAC 1160

#### TUTOR (COMPUTING) - WA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY (1982 - 1982)

- Lectured PASCAL to students
- Tutored programming concepts

Marked & accessed the students

# TUTOR (COMPUTER SCIENCE) - RMIT UNIVERSITY (1978 – 1980)

- Lectured FORTRAN to Engineering students
- Tutored PASCAL to Computer Science students
- Tutored first year Computer Science students in Assembly programming using a Motorola 6800
- Wrote a program as supporting code for a paper published by the IEEE

## **ORGANISATIONS**

- Member of the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)
- Member of the Institute of Electrical & Electronics Engineers (IEEE)
- Member of the IEEE Computer Society
- Member of the Planetary Society